## DANIEL REY

+63-966-2674-689 · <u>danielrey.vercel.app</u> · <u>@danielrey</u> · <u>reyvillanuevadaniel@gmail.com</u> L4 B8 Ecology Subdivision Vinzons Camarines Norte

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Hello, I'm Daniel. I am a professional software engineer with experience in developing various web and Android applications. I have a strong background in scaling products to meet client needs and integrating APIs into both web and mobile platforms, which has helped me gain a solid understanding of common challenges in development. With years of experience in building robust applications, I have successfully navigated a range of technical issues. I am confident that my skills and commitment would make me a valuable asset to your team.

## **SKILLS**

Javascript | HTML | CSS | React | Tailwind | NextJS

Java | Go | Python Django | MySQL | PostgreSQL | SQLite | Firebase

Figma | Adobe XD | Postman

## **EXPERIENCE**

# DEVEX - A Quadruple A Construction Company Web Developer

August 2023 - Present

- Created an internal software for productivity and optimization of works. Used by over a hundred employees.
- The software has 3 systems inside of it that is tailored for specific department. Each system(module) has different features and specific use cases.
- When developing this I used: Figma, Next.js 14, React.js with Typescript, Tailwind, PHP Laravel for backend and MySQL for the database.

## Thesis: An android based app for maternal health reproductive Android Developer

2022 - 2023

- Features: Video Recommendations containing maternal health videos, Realtime Chat w/ notification for seamless chat and experience, Chatbot for emergency questions with reliable response. Online schedule consultation for hassle free user.
- I received Senior BSCS: SE of the year 2023 award and our thesis awarded as Best Thesis
- I used Java, Firebase, SQLite, Adobe XD, Postman, and GCP

March 2022 - May 2022

## Fastlane Start-up Company (Intern)

#### **Backend Developer**

- Maintain the existing software by developing modularized models and business logic which allowed for easy unit testing.
- · Migrating the database from SQLite to PostgreSQL.
- We used Python Django, HTML, CSS(SCSS, Bootstrap), JS
- · Maintain Point of Sale and Credit Management for Fastlane client.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Mabini Colleges Inc.

2019 - 2023

mabiiii ooneges iiio.

## **CERTIFICATES**

Bootstrap Certifications

**HTML and CSS Certifications**